Thank you.
Montezara…
Five. Track five.
Can I help? Can I help you
with the baby up the stairs?
What?
- I'll take the bottom.
- Sì. Grazie.
It's okay. All right. Hi!
Oh my goodness, look at you!
Good, you made it in one piece.
No. Not yet.
I can barely find this town on the map.
Well hey, you took
your first vacation day in years.
Trust me, no trip to Italy
can be considered a vacation.
- Okay, not again with "the curse."
- Hey.
The curse is real.
I came after college. I lost my passport.
I came back on my honeymoon.
We both got the flu,
and it rained every day.
Frankly, I can't believe
Liv's made it this long.
It's a good thing I saw on her Instagram
that she wants to buy this one-euro house.
- I thought she bought it already?
- No, not if I can help it.
I'm here to find my daughter
and bring her home.
You're Eric Field in Italy,
not Liam Neeson in Taken.
Yeah, that's fair.
Oh, hey, uh, I sent you
a pitch presentation for Northstar.
Great. Then relax. Take in the scenery.
- All right, talk to you later.
- Yeah, we'll talk soon.
I knew I should've made
my Instagram private.
You know, the daughter I used to know
would open with, "Hi, Dad."
Hi, Dad.
I'll take it. Hug for your old man?
Come on.
Thank you.
Why are you here? I thought Italy
was the one place you'd never come.
Well, I'm making an exception for you,
my loving daughter,
who took off in the dead of night.
- It's called a red-eye.
- With barely a word.
- I sent you a very detailed WhatsApp.
- What's up? What?
- You disappeared.
- I'm on social media every day.
Then you somehow end up
buying an Italian villa?
If you meant to activate
the Dad bat signal...
- I didn't.
- Well, you did. Big time.
You know what? Suit yourself, BatDad.
I'm gonna drop you off at the hotel.
I'm meeting the mayor
to go house shopping.
- House shopping?
- Mm-hmm.
So it's not a done deal?
Excellent. I'm not too late.
You think you're gonna stop me?
I need coffee for this.
Well, look, I assumed you'd get Italy
out of your system. Eat some pizza.
See some ruins. Use your college Italian
to charm some cute waiters.
- You assumed. Never asked.
- How could I? I never hear from you.
- I was busy working.
- Mm-hmm.
I tutored English in Milan.
I nannied in Florence.
I spent some time harvesting olives.
A couple weeks ago,
I was on the way to a wine festival gig.
I got on the wrong train by accident
and ended up here.
And it was like… boom!
Like "boom" what?
I'm missing a few steps from that story.
Mm. It's hard to explain.
You have to feel it.
- Montezara's a feeling.
- All I feel is jet lag.
Can we fast-forward
to the whole "bought a villa" nonsense?
It's a real thing.
Small towns are selling old houses
for one euro to bring new people in.
The mayor was telling me
all about the whole scheme.
Well, at least you admit it's a scheme.
So I put in an application,
got accepted, and I'm a Montezaran now.
- But I assumed...
- There's that word again.
You would be coming back to Ohio.
You'd get roommates,
a paycheck, dental insurance.
You know, adulting.
Isn't owning a house
the very definition of adulting?
Honey,
I had to come open up the cafe.
I understand but sometimes
I think you love this café more than me.
- I love you both equally.
- Equally, Cesare!? Are you serious?
- No, actually…
- Really?
- Not equally…
- I can't take this!
- Oh!
- These friends of yours?
Cesare and Donata. They break up
almost every day like clockwork.
- Ciao, Olivia.
- Ciao.
- Hi, Cesare.
- Hey.
Two coffees, please.
- Thanks.
- Nico, two coffees for Olivia.
- You're welcome.
Maybe today this beauty
will finally join me for a coffee.
Charm doesn't work on me, Giovanni.
I've never
struck out so bad before.
Eh!
It's good to have new experiences.
Ooh!
- I'll pay for the coffees.
- Oh, thank you.
But, you know, home owner ship's
a little more expensive than coffee.
I was thinking of using
the fund Mom set aside for me.
Well, that's all tied up in investments.
You'd have to sell, then you'd owe taxes.
There's another adulting word.
You know, you're not really selling me
on the whole adulting thing.
Well, last I checked,
you were an adult, Liv.
Hey, come on, you ju...
Kids, huh?
They sure know how to drive you insane.
You try to give them space.
Let them find their own way.
Be the cool dad. But that also means
being not cool about bad ideas.
Not like she ever asks my opinion,
which is how she got duped into this
one-euro house scam in the first place...
- Oh, great! You two have met.
- What?
Dad, this is Francesca Pucci.
Mayor of Montezara.
Welcome to Italy, Mr. Field.
Ah, shoot.
- BatDad, what'd you do now?
- I sense he wants to back out.
- Yes, exactly. We're backing out.
- No, we are not backing out.
We've already started the paperwork
and have accepted her 5,000 euro deposit.
5,000 euros?
I thought the house was one euro.
Deposits are standard procedure
for Italian villa programs.
To ensure the work'll be finished.
I put it on my card. The town'll refund me
once the work's done.
- So this really is a racket.
- Dad, I'm looking at houses today.
All right?
A moment alone, please.
Why are you so set on this?
When Mom was in the hospital,
we'd look up one-euro villas online…
…all the befores and afters,
and talk about what we'd do differently.
We were gonna apply when she got better.
Yeah, I thought that was just
a… daydream to get through a tough time.
It was just a daydream
to get through a tough time,
which is why I wanna make it a reality.
Mom was always very proud
to be part Italian,
and being in Italy
makes me feel closer to her.
Why didn't you
tell me this before?
Right, because I don't listen.
All right.
Francesca?
Okay! Let's go see
what a buck buys around here.
House
number one.
Wait.
Yes!
Ah!
The one-euro price tag makes sense now.
For one euro,
you expect the Sistine Chapel?
So it… it just needs a little TLC.
Uh-huh.
Oh! I think we can move on.
Right this way.
House number two.
Oh! Well, it's light and airy.
No, for a euro,
I don't expect the Sistine Chapel.
But I do expect a ceiling.
Huh, comes with roommates.
I think we can move on. Quick.
Seriously?
Nino is a genius at renovations.
Nino, Francesca's brother-in-law
is my contractor.
Ah!
So this is a family racket.
Uh, excuse me. Just a moment.
Liv, even with a genius contractor,
you realize that DIY means do-it-yourself?
Mm-hmm. I'll learn on the job.
It's so different than nannying
or working at a renaissance fair.
I get the dream.
But sometimes reality,
it can be a tough wake-up call.
Matteo, can you hear me?
Yes, Francesca, yes, hello…
I'm here with a man
from the road maintenance company.
Montezara's check bounced again.
Just grab the emergency credit card,
in the bottom drawer of the desk.
It's stuck.
Give it a kick!
Nope, not even now…
Harder! Understand?
Harder… yes.
Here we go… yes!
Thank you, Francesca.
Good. Good, good.
Write off the 5,000 euros
as an expensive life lesson,
and let's go home.
I have
another house to show you.
It's not on the official one-euro list,
but, Olivia, I think you will like it.
Let's go, girl.
Like it? I love it. Wow!
It's beautiful.
I mean, look at the olive trees.
- Why is this one not a total wreck?
- The owner died just last year.
An eccentric old man we used to call
Marioil Burbero. "Mario the Grumpy."
Oh, Maltese!
Here you are, you silly goat.
It used to be Mario's pet.
Now the town takes turns feeding her.
I'll throw her in with the one euro.
Can I pay a euro to take her away?
Oh, it's big.
Yeah.
Awesome ceilings.
The house was built
by a noted local architect, Greco.
Come.
There are bedrooms.
There is electricity, plumbing.
Both are a bit old, but they work.
And there is even a fresco.
Grumpy Mario painted it himself.
- Huh! It's actually kind of beautiful.
- Mm.
Sweet.
A legit Italian room with a view.
Wait. Is this the kitchen?
Grumpy Mario wasn't much of a cook.
He relied on this old microwave.
Oh, Mario, I feel you, man.
Punching in two minutes
is the go-to move when you live alone.
Way to be depressing, Dad.
- Oh, what? You don't cook.
- I know, but you do. Or did.
Dad has a secret that before
he was a boring restaurant consultant,
he was a professional chef.
Full of surprises.
But then I switched to the corporate side
to take care of my family.
But even now,
you still haven't gone back to cheffing.
I like cooking for you instead.
That's funny.
You haven't cooked for me in ages.
Well, that would require
you coming over for dinner. Ever.
Well, I gotta say, you, uh,
you certainly saved the best for last.
Well, the villa
is not on the official list yet.
Mario died a bachelor with no will.
We're supposed to clear
the estate succession before showing it.
You sure he didn't
secretly leave this place to that goat?
His Italian relatives were not interested.
You know, too much hassle, too far away.
And any possible distant relatives
never returned any calls or emails,
so it was just now donated to Montezara.
This is the place. I can feel it.
So do we have a sale?
You couldn't have a normal
quarter-life crisis and get a tattoo?
I already did.
- Old news.
- What? Where?
- What?
- Don't worry about it.
Then I guess… …it looks like
we have a one-euro house.
Great!
What?
You're staying?
Yeah, I need to help Liv
get this renovation off the ground.
- A couple weeks, a month tops.
- A month?!
You would miss the Northstar pitch.
We're up against Perfect Plate Consulting.
Right. Right. Well, maybe
you can pitch the Northstar execs.
I mean, Zola, you're ready.
Eric, you know you're the closer.
They'll expect you in the room.
We can prep visuals and menus over Zoom.
You've always been more charming than me.
Well, flattery might get you somewhere.
- But you better hurry that Reno along.
- Yeah.
All right, Eric Field,
living large in an Italian villa.
- Who'd have thunk it?
- Not Liv, that's for sure.
- Uh, let's talk tomorrow. Yep.
- Mm-hmm.
Hey. I thought you were unpacking.
Uh, yeah. Just finished.
- Well, you could put things away.
- Then how would I know where anything is?
Right. Right.
You know, the hotel is free of all
my clutter. Why don't you stay there?
- Well, I didn't want you to be alone.
- I'm not. I'm going out.
I am meeting up with Donata
to yet again hear about her breakup saga.
Oh. Okay.
Okay.
Hey, don't be out too late. Early start!
MINI PIZZAS
Oh!
- Uh, Stracciatella, per favore.
- Of course.
That's my favorite too.
Oh, hey.
- I've actually never tried it.
- Eric, meet Bernardo.
Bernardo, meet Eric, Olivia's father.
I'll be at your renovation kickoff meeting
with Nino tomorrow.
- Oh.
- Bernardo is our localgeometra.
You don't have them in America.
It's like, um…
- Property expert.
- Ah.
We're, uh, required
on every Italian construction project.
Sounds good. All help is welcome.
Looks like that
is the last scoop ofstracciatella.
You take it, Madam Mayor.
No, no, no.
It's the quintessential gelato flavor.
- I'd be a terrible mayor if I took it.
- Consider it a peace offering.
I was not on my best behavior earlier.
- Please.
- Ecco.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Of course.
And I'll have chocolate, if you're buying.
Uh, yeah, of course.
Uh, du... duo ci... cioccolato, per favore.
Your Italian, it's, um…
It's in process, yes.
I figured I'm here for a while,
maybe make an effort.
- Grazie.
- Good evening.
Bernardo, may I have a moment
about my expansion permit?
Excuse us.
That's Giovanni Rosada,
a local chef. Very talented.
- Let's sit.
- Yep.
- Mm.
- Here.
- Oh, you…
- Oh.
- You have a little…
- Always.
- It's more there.
- Got it? I… I'm hopeless.
Thank you.
Please, give my regards to Olivia.
- Ciao.
Already did some tourist shopping?
Ah. Yeah. It's…
…precious cargo.
Well, I'd better get my dinner home.
You weren't kidding about the microwave.
You do realize you're in Italy, right?
I do, yeah, but it's Italian frozen pizza.
See you guys.
He's nice, right?
He's American…
So, Grumpy Mario's house?
That's a gamble.
Especially not on the official list.
Bernardo, the young people
are all moving away.
To Rome, Milan.
We have to do something to save our town.
So the solution is for strangers
with frozen pizza to take over?
Think of it as them joining us,
not taking over.
If I want to get the asses sore
to back my new initiatives,
I need this first one-euro house
to be a total success.
All right.
Good morning, sunshine.
Where am I? Oh!
What time is it?
8:30.
Nino's already been here an hour.
Early start, remember?
Yeah. Uh, it was the time change
and my alarm didn't…
- You're enjoying this small humiliation.
- Yeah.
- Pants.
- What?
- You're gonna need pants.
- Oh.
Oh.
Long night with the microwave?
You already know me so well.
I didn't know you'd be here today.
Of course I'm here.
It's like the first day of school.
Buongiorno.
- You must be Eric.
- Yeah.
- Nino.
- Hey.
Rad choice. Best villa in town!
- You say that about every place?
- Sì.
I put together a schedule and a budget.
- I'll get us a whiteboard.
- Dad, slow your roll way down.
Whose renovation is this anyway?
Well, I thought
that I could front you the money.
That is until you get
those investment accounts sold off.
You will need some cash up-front.
My credit card is maxed out.
Okay. But I'll pay you back
as soon as I can. Thanks.
Until then, I vote that me and Amex
get some input. We have experience.
Yeah, consulting on commercial kitchens.
It's totally different
from what Nino and I've been discussing,
which is the feel.
We were thinking modernized,
but maintain the OG charm.
- Brava.
- Mm-hmm.
I like the way this one talks.
And I'll take the lead
on cultivating the garden out back.
- Come on.
- Okay.
Yep, this is perfect. Right here.
Garden? All I see is a junkyard.
Mom always kept a garden.
I'm carrying on the family legacy.
It'll be fully sustainable, and I want
the entire Reno to be eco-friendly.
Sustainability is one
of my primary goals here in Montezara.
Yeah, look, this is fun stuff,
but can we get serious for a second?
What do we need? Who do we need?
We need an electrician. A roofer.
- Uh, we need a plumber.
- No, man. That's me. I'm on it.
- Nino's a jack-of-all-trades.
- Sì.
I got you covered.
He's got me covered.
Okay. Well, we will just see what we need
as we go. I'm happy to steer the ship.
Dad. My house. My helm.
Sì.We will make this
a far-out dream villa.
- But first, permits.
- Yes.
And there are many, many permits
in our famous Italian bureaucracy.
Then it's a good thing
I'm here to save the day.
- Hey.
- Bernardo.
But before I pull any permits,
let me see the plans.
Demo. Plumbing. Plaster.
Painting. Restore the fresco.
Yeah, and we wanna build a real kitchen.
It's all doable. Standard-issue permits.
It should just take, uh, six months.
- What?
I know. Pretty fast, huh?
Bernardo, promise me
you'll do what you can to speed things up.
You know what this means for Montezara.
- Catching this?
- Work your magic.
How can I say no to you, ladybug?
You guys can start the work.
Oh!
The infamous Eric Field whiteboard.
- Dad, I don't need your schedule.
- You need a schedule.
Yes, but the villa sets the schedule.
Nino and I have to feel it.
So what have I missed?
Oh, I love the calendar.
- It's so well organized.
- See? Someone likes it.
- Mm.
- Nino, perfect timing.
I want to show you and Olivia
this new renovation software I use.
- I did a mock-up.
- Nino, can you please put me to work?
Anything to avoid
my dad's upcoming PowerPoint.
- It's not a PowerPoint. It's a simulation.
- See? I am out.
That's nice.
- Uh, you know, I've got this.
- Of course.
- I was just trying to help.
- I understand. Yep.
Okay, let's try moving
the food supply page before the menu...
- Hi!
- Oh.
- Oh, sorry to interrupt.
- Yep.
- Carry on.
- Thank you.
Who's the hottie?
Uh, it's just the mayor.
That's the mayor? Dang.
Now the 30-day stay is making sense.
Who, her? No. No! No, she's a pain.
Really. Total micro manager.
Mm. Sounds like
you two have a lot in common.
All right, next panel, please.
Hey!
- It's so much fun marking off the days.
- Yeah, I know.
Don't you have
city hall work to, you know, get to?
I do. I tagged along with Bernardo,
but I'm heading off now.
- Ah.
- Yeah, so… ciao.
Ciao. Are you guys doing
an electrical safety check?
- Well, the EU has very high standards.
- Hey, question.
- You can appraise property value, right?
- Of course. Why do you ask?
Well, you know, in case we...
in case Olivia wants
to do a quick flip and sell.
- That'd be the wise move.
- I agree.
But good luck convincing Olivia
or Francesca.
So, uh, Francesca. Here a lot, huh?
More than I expected, frankly.
That's just Francesca's way.
She's always been the one in charge.
- So you two are close?
- Very.
She's a special woman.
It's almost like you guys
are Montezara's power couple.
- You could say that.
- Hey, Bernardo!
- Excuse me.
- Of course. Yeah.
Engineered hardwood
is richer and more authentic.
Yeah, and more authentically expensive.
And it's hard to install.
I don't think we'll need either.
Whoa.
It's beautiful.
Wow. That's the kind
of vintage detail that attracts buyers.
Buyers?
What buyers?
Dad, I told you. I am not selling.
Liv, please. You're 24.
What are you gonna do?
Live in this sleepy town forever?
Yeah. My generation's experience
with adulting hasn't been so great.
No job stability.
No health insurance. No, thank you.
- What period are they from?
- The late 1800s.
I always imagined my house
with Moroccan tiles.
Nino!
- Aye?
- Come here.
What's that?
A chimney.
But there's no fireplace
in that part of the house.
Huh.
A job forL'Orso Grasso.
The fat bear?
Yeah.
Oh!
Good job! Another hit! Go!
Olivia, be careful.
- Don't worry. Fat bear's got it.
- Just… Whoa!
Put your body into it.
Yeah!
Hey!
- Whoa, whoa. You okay?
- Yeah.
Wow!
Why would anyone cover this up?
Drafts. Birds nesting.
Crazy, man.
Wow. I mean… this is a real brick oven.
Like, for pizzas.
This must've been part
of the original kitchen.
- Are you seeing dollar signs again?
- What? No.
No, I was noodling on plans
for a kitchen makeover earlier.
But this takes it to a whole new level.
Are there original blueprints? I wanna see
if there's anything else we're missing.
Possibly. At City Hall.
- Good luck finding them.
- Challenge accepted.
Maybe I'll drop in on the mayor
for a change. Fastest way to town?
- Uh… Ah, Grumpy Mario had abicicletta.
- Okay.
I think it's in the shed out back.
His nickname for her was "Vecchia Strega."
"Vecchia"means "old," right?
But"Strega"?
Witch. Old Witch.
Old…
…Witch.
Whoa.
Ignore him.
All right.
Good morning, ladies.
Good morning!
Why are you speaking to him?
I'm being polite.
But he's a stranger!
A handsome stranger.
So now you're the town flirt?
Mm. Don't fall for those eyes.
- Eh, eh, eh.
- These Americans are here to ruin us!
Hi. Hi.
Is there ariparo bicicletta,
um…negozio?
You're just gonna make me
keep talking, aren't you?
- Typical American.
- I understood that.
Arrogant.
Thinks everyone speaks English.
Fine by me, I like them cocky.
And so fit.
That's enough.
Hey!
Vecchia Strega!
A local legend rides again.
I have a repair kit. Come on.
Thank you.
You must've taken quite a spill.
- Yeah, well, it's the curse.
- The curse?
Long story.
- Are we today's free entertainment?
- The Antonias?
- What?
- All three of them are named Antonia.
And they love a good show.
And they just sit
at that fountain all day?
All day. Il dolce far niente.
"The sweetness of doing nothing."
Never heard of that.
It's a popular concept
here in Italy.
Not a personal habit of mine.
Yeah, I hear you. I own a company,
so workaholic's part of the job.
- Why is workaholic such a bad word?
- Ah, please.
- We keep the world running.
- Yes!
- Thank you. We keep the world running.
- Pronta! As good as new.
Well… …thank you.
I don't think anything on this has been
new for 50 years, but I appreciate it.
Hey, I'm on a mission
to find original blueprints to the villa.
I'll race you to theMunicipio.
- Won't be much of a race.
- Come on.
- Worried I'll beat you on this thing?
- No. We're already here.
This is my parking spot.
Oh.
- Matteo, my assistant. Mr. Eric Field.
- Salve.
Whoa.
I can't find anything if it's put away.
You're just like Olivia.
I knew I liked her. Here it is.
The revitalization meeting
with theAssessore Provinciale'sstaff
is in ten minutes.
Should I spike their coffee with grappa?
Matteo, please.
Let's go.
Dio mio.
- Right through here.
- Yeah.
Here we are.
Well, this makes your office
look positively organized.
There was a flood and everything
got moved around to different places.
It's probably in here somewhere.
Good luck.
Oh dear, no…
What?
- It can't be.
- We'll just call for help.
- It's okay.
- We can't. There's no reception in here.
I can't miss my meeting,
and theAssessore Provinciale'soffice
isn't very understanding.
Okay. Let me. Let me. Whoa, whoa.
- Let me just, um... I'll... Okay.
- Please.
On three. One. Two. Three.
Whoa!
Madam Mayor?
- -Your guests are here.
- Yes.
I was just finishing up a tour
with our American guest.
- Please, right this way.
- Well, they seem fun.
Hey, maybe have some
of that grappa in your coffee.
- Ciao.
- Buongiorno, Eric.
- Buongiorno.
Eric, how's the renovation going?
Uh, loud and messy. I tell you what.
You take your broom to the villa.
- I'll stay here and pull espresso shots.
- Ah. Don't worry. I got you.
Thanks. We're looking forward to this.
- Bye-bye.
- Yep.
Frigging Northstar, our clients!
I guess you crushed
that presentation, huh?
Yep. My phone is just blowing up.
Even Deb Welch
from Perfect Plate texted congrats.
Really? She didn't text me.
Hold up. Is the competition
trying to poach you?
Oh, come on now. So when will you be back?
Yeah, about that.
Um, I think…
- Uh…
- Oh, Eric.
- Yes?
- I need you here.
- Of course.
- Oh.
Speak of the devil. It's Deb.
- What?
- Don't worry.
I'll blow her off.
Gotta go.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Hey, Nino.
No luck yet with the blueprints.
We can still start re-piping.
First, we remove grody old pipes.
Adesso, dig in.
Dig in? To what? Wait. Oh, you mean me?
Yes, you pitch in now.
I hold. You get a fun job.
- Sawing.
- Sawing's a fun job. Yes, sure.
- Come on.
- I ju... Okay. All right.
- Okay.
- Right here?
Yes.
So, hey, Francesca,
she's your sister-in-law, right?
- Your marriage, or…
- No, not me.
She was married to my brother, Alessandro.
- Oh.
- He passed five years ago.
- Heart attack.
- Mm.
Totally out of the blue.
I'm so sorry.
I know what that's like. My, uh…
My wife died three years ago.
It's… it's a crappy club to be a part of.
You know,
you are single, Francesca is single…
Oh, I thought... Well, she and Bernardo…
Bernardo? All I know is no one
has touched her heart since Alessandro.
That's intriguing,
but I'm not in the market.
- In the market for what?
- Oh, Francesca.
Madam Mayor.
Just in time to save me from… this.
- I don't know. It looks like fun.
- Uh…
Uh… I have to go now.
Olivia's calling me.
No, she's not.
Here, let me help.
No, you're all dressed…
So? Ginger Rogers
did everything Fred Astaire did,
but backwards and in heels, right?
All right, Madam Mayor, let's dance.
Show me what you got.
Uh, I have a confession to make.
I am not a DIY guy.
I got you.
I actually got stuck in our chimney once,
trying to shoo a squirrel out.
Of course, that was the day
Liv realized Santa's not real,
because if Dad can't fit
in the chimney, how can Santa?
- Oh man. Oh, here, wait. I got you.
- How disgusting!
I know, I know. Here.
- Thank you.
- Some dance pair we are, huh?
Oh Dio! Dio! I turned off water.
Must be some left in the pipe.
I'm so sorry, Francesca.
I'm so sorry!
Seriously?
You're listing the villa
after everything we talked about?
No! No. I'm just…
I'm looking at comps,
you know, in the area.
Here. Investments liquidated.
A check for everything I owe you
minus the taxes. See?
I do know that adult word.
- Thanks, Liv. But look, I think...
- I think it's time for you to go.
It's barely been a month.
I can stay a bit longer.
Dad, you came to talk me outta this place.
And then, when you couldn't do that,
you went on some sort of weird campaign
to convince me to try to sell it.
Once it's done, what are you gonna do?
How are you gonna support yourself?
BatDads worry.
I'll figure it out.
- What you planting?
- Over here's lavender.
And then all of this will be rosemary
because they're both edible
and pollinator friendly.
You want some help?
- Listen, I was thinking...
- Can you not talk?
Please?
For, like, a second.
Can we just… garden?
♪ And I want to go to bed ♪
♪ I had a little drink about an hour ago ♪
♪ And it's gone straight to my head ♪
♪ Wherever I may roam ♪
♪ On land or sea or foam ♪
♪ You always hear me singing that song ♪
♪ Show me the way to go ♪
♪ Show me the way to go home ♪
- Oh.
- Yes!
God!
I've not sung that in ages.
Listen, maybe you're right.
Maybe I've overstayed my welcome.
But if my time here in Italy
is coming to a close,
uh… you know, I can give up the work Zooms
and frozen pizza for one night.
We should go to dinner.
You and me?
Well, I mean,
Maltese's probably had her fill, so…
I'd love that.
Okay.
This is it.
All right.
Welcome.
- Thank you.
- Perfect, thank you.
Buonasera. Welcome to my restaurant.
Donata, the VIP table
by the kitchen for my special guests.
- Sure, follow me.
- VIP treatment.
- All right.
- Way to play my dad, Gio.
Since you won't join me for acaffé,
I must go to extraordinary lengths.
Prego.
There you go.
Thank you.
- That's a localBrunello di Montalcino.
- Mmm.
Allora, Eric, I hear
you're in the restaurant business too.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, well, not like this. I consult.
- Consult?
- Mm-hmm.
What does this mean?
Um, I advise restaurant clients
on how to improve operations.
Everything from budgets to new menus to...
Please, it just means he doesn't cook
when he should be cooking.
Well, here we have aprimo
ofmaltagliatiwith porcini mushrooms.
- A regional specialty. Enjoy.
- Wow. Thank you.
Uh, you from around here, Giovanni?
I grew up in Rome,
but I have family in Montezara.
- That why you opened your restaurant here?
- She's finally curious about me.
Just making polite conversation
in close quarters.
I was a sous-chef in Rome,
but I always dreamed
of having my own place,
somewhere I could
feed guests my family recipes.
This pasta is so light,
but the depth of flavor.
Am I tasting
melted anchovies in the olive oil?
- Impressive palate, Eric.
- Still got it, Dad.
Buon appetito.
Thank you.
These condo tonight
is freshly cut branzino
stuffed with herbs
and baked in a salt crust.
Ooh!
Grazie, Fabio.
Mmm. I know these techniques.
I don't know how you get these flavors.
I'm in awe. Or heaven, I can't decide.
Why don't you come by between lunch
and dinner service sometime?
I can show you sometrucchetti toscani.
- Sounds great.
- All right.
Delicious. Thank you.
- Ciao.
- That was great.
- Bye.
Oh.
Okay.
All part of your charm offensive?
Why, is it finally working?
I'll let you know.
Is the gang all here?
Guys, come in. Come on.
So, what's the emergency?
Well, Liv and I had
the most fantastic meal
atTrattoria Rosada.
Congratulations,
you've enjoyed real pasta.
- Can we go now?
- No, no, not yet.
I realized this remodel reminds me
of these clients I worked with.
A chef couple who bought
this old craftsman in Columbus.
Where is this going, Dad?
They completely upgraded their kitchen,
where they now teach cooking classes.
Are you saying to do
something like that here in this villa?
Is that even possible?
- No, it is not.
- Wait, hear me out.
So, instead of dumping
Grumpy Mario's sad microwave,
we build out
an entire commercial-grade kitchen,
starting from the brick oven.
But who will teach?
Surely not Americans. Come on.
Well, we hire local chefs.
Make this place the real deal.
Guys, I can help recruit.
I do it all the time for work.
- Local chefs. Local food.
- Mm-hmm.
A cooking school
would be a big tourist draw.
Sì.Show how special Montezara is
through our cuisine.
Okay. Okay, I'm vibing with it, yeah.
Cooking classes require
a change-of-use permit.
And these permits
are very, very difficult to come by.
Well, that's where you come in, Bernardo.
You're our secret weapon.
I mean, you have the permit office
under your spell.
We'll see.
We'll put the dish pit here,
out of sight of the prep and dining areas.
We'll have a double-door refrigerator,
standing freezer,
and then a gas stove over here,
and two electric ranges.
Mm-hmm. I dig it.
Thank you.
Dad, this is great, but is it necessary?
I mean, I don't think I can afford it.
I've got a little fund of my own.
Uh, money I've been saving for,
honestly, I don't know what,
but now it seems like it's
for top-of-the-line Italian appliances.
I'm never getting rid of you, am I?
- I can still go.
- No. No.
I don't know anything about
commercial kitchens. I need you.
- Oh.
- Not permanently.
Just for a little while longer.
I haven't made pasta in ages. I've been
relying on stuff you get from a box.
No, don't say this. Come on.
That'sorrendo.
No good food ever comes from cardboard.
Yeah, I know.
I used to make everything homemade.
Olivia and my wife, Mia,
keeping me company in the kitchen.
Oh, we would throw
these huge dinner parties,
and Olivia would wear
this cute little fake mustache
and write out a chalkboard menu.
Our mini maître d'.
- And you don't do this anymore?
- No, no. Uh…
- Well, Olivia outgrew the mustache.
- Oh, well.
And, you know, life changed when we, uh…
When we found out that Mia had cancer.
Cooking sort of lost its joy for me.
Well, how does it feel cooking now?
It feels like where I'm supposed to be.
Well, welcome back home, Eric.
Thanks, man. You know,
the plans for the villa have changed.
We're now putting in a commercial kitchen
in the hopes of teaching cooking classes.
Wow.
Yeah, I dunno.
Maybe you'd consider teaching?
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
- Olivia asked for me to teach there?
- Uh…
Well… you know, she loves the idea
of locals sharing their knowledge.
Wonderful, yeah. Sign me up.
Great.
Hey, what about this one?
Boring.
So, Gio. That guy likes you.
Ugly. Pass.
Gio or the tile?
Oh, come on, he's a good guy.
Talented. Kind.
Better than that old boyfriend
of yours, Frisbee Brad.
There is nothing wrong
with being an aspiring
professional ultimate Frisbee player.
Sure, yeah. Uh, what's he doing now?
Aspiring to play
professional ultimate Frisbee.
There you go.
Sì! That's it.
Totally the villa's vibe.
Modern but traditional.
- Yeah, that's what I was thinking!
- I'm gonna quit while I'm ahead. I'm off.
You are a natural at this, Olivia.
Design and flow. Soul.
Thank you.
That's very nice of you to say.
I'm not being nice, huh?
You thought of studying it seriously?
Uh… no. No, I haven't thought about that.
Until right now.
I have a talented designer friend in Rome.
Yes, he takes on apprentices.
If you're interested.
I don't… I don't know. Am I interested?
Maybe.
Yeah, maybe I am.
You know, for the past few years,
I've felt sort of… adrift.
Like I've been trying to find
something to do with my life.
I don't know. I just convinced
my dad the villa was a good idea.
Won't it look like I'm bailing?
If in doubt, paddle out.
- Nino surfer wisdom?
- Sì!
Wait.
- You mean like catch the wave?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Let me think about it, okay?
No rush. Let me know.
Say, "A table for two, please."
Un tavolo per due, per favore.
Mmm. Giuliano Montaldo,
ah, now, that was a beautiful man.
Good morning, ladies.
Uh, beautiful day today.
I still don't understand.
Plugs up and down our historical roads?
We've gone over this.
The tourists are the ones
asking for charging stations.
Rental car fleets are all going electric.
Ah, our… …American resident.
Eric, you're on urgent business?
Uh, yes.
Yes. Oh, yeah, it's very, very urgent…
Uh… my apologies…
Um, I…
I require the mayor's assistance.
Matteo can answer
any remaining questions, gentlemen.
Mm-hmm.
- Thank you.
- Prego.
Best hideout in City Hall.
We'll wait out those guys
looking for your old blueprint.
- I'll leave the door cracked open.
- Yeah, yeah.
So being a female mayor around here,
that can't be easy.
We are a rare breed here in Italy,
which makes getting
my agenda off the ground a lot harder.
Mm. Then why be mayor?
- My late husband, Alessandro, was mayor.
- Oh.
Many years ago.
Is this him?
Not that many years ago.
Tell me about him, Alessandro.
He was kind.
Outgoing.
- Stubborn.
- Hmm.
He would always get us lost
and never ask for directions.
Well, that's a universal guy thing.
We'll confidently walk off a cliff
before admitting we're wrong.
- And he was an excellent dancer.
- Oh. That's not a universal guy thing.
You will not catch me on a dance floor.
After he was gone,
people encouraged me to take over,
but, you know,
there's too much politics in politics.
Yeah. What changed your mind?
I got tired of waiting for someone
to step in and save Montezara.
I gotta admit,
in the beginning, I kept wondering,
"Why is the mayor
micromanaging this villa renovation?"
I wasn't micromanaging.
Okay, I was micromanaging.
But only because I need everything
to go absolutely perfect.
Mm-hmm. Because you love this town.
I'm scared for this town.
We're almost broke.
- But you know something?
- Hmm?
Anything worth loving
is worth fighting for.
Yes.
And, um, how about Olivia's mother?
Mia. Yeah, she, um…
She was an original.
From the instant I met her, I found myself
doing things I could never imagine.
Like eating raisins.
Your love story is raisins?
Well, I always hated them.
On our first date,
we decided we wanted to go hiking.
We met at her place for breakfast,
and she made oatmeal with raisins.
And somehow, I ate it all up.
The path to true love is never smooth.
No. Yeah, mine was paved with raisins.
She knew you really loved her.
She was myraisin d'être.
- Oh no.
- It's a play on the French.
- Raison d'être.
- I get it. I get it. It's just terrible.
I know. Hey, I think this might be it.
- Greco?
- Yeah.
Yes, Greco was the architect.
There. Leoni. Look at this.
Please be right. Please.
Yes!
See? I knew it. Look, the villa
originally had a spacious kitchen.
You know, it almost feels like
the cooking school was meant to be.
That is if we ever get
the change-of-use permit.
Bernardo's been kind of MIA.
Really? I'll take care of it.
Grazie.
I've been wondering.
Are there any other one-euro houses
that have also doubled as businesses?
- Yes, there's one in Cossari.
- Oh.
It's an old Tuscan castle.
It got a makeover,
and now it's a luxury boutique hotel.
- Can we go check it out?
- Meet tomorrow morning?
It's a date.
Really?
Uh…
That's a saying in America.
People say that.
They say it all the time. Yeah.
Okay, then. It's a date.
Hello, ladies.
Uh, I'm Eric Field.
- He's speaking Italian!
- Badly.
Rome wasn't built in a day.
I'm come for advisory.
You know here around everything.
- That we do.
- Antonia!
But we do, and he's making an effort.
What do you need, young man?
Uh… I'm going on a picnic.
With Francesca?
Aha!
I called that on day one.
Pay up, sister. I won the bet.
Come on, pay up.
Grifter.
Okay, then. Uh, uh…
What are
some of the mayor's favorites?
She's a fan ofProsciutto di Cinta.
- Also a little Got a.
- Gota, okay.
Get some local Capri no del Maremmacheese.
Only insiders know about that.
- She'll be impressed.
- Sì? Ah.
Like he'll remember any of this.
Men have terrible memories.
Because of their much smaller brains.
We'll write a list for you.
Okay,
I think I'm following that.
You'll also need this.
Oh, this is perfect.Grazie.
Allora, these are the approved
historical Montezara house colors.
Okay.
I think I like the tone of this one.
- This one?
- Yeah, it's nice and rich.
- Yeah, let's go with that, for sure.
- Good choice. Very good choice.
Nino, you know, about that apprenticeship,
I think I want to paddle out… and apply.
Awesome, Olivia!
I'll put you in touch.
You know, this…
this wave finally feels… right.
Did you tell your dad that?
No.
Where is he, by the way?
- I have no idea. He left early today.
- Hmm.
Vecchia Stregainspired me.
Good thing she can't see us right now.
She's the jealous type.
Hey, how soon do we need to get back?
Well, I micromanaged my calendar
with fake meetings all afternoon.
Well played, Madam Mayor.
Whoo!
Wow, this place sets the bar high.
Come, I'll buy you
an overpricedcafféwith a view.
I like the wrought iron work.
That looks nice in here.
Sorry, apologies.
We are closed today for a private event.
- Prego.
- Thank you.
- We are seeing this hotel today.
- We rode our bikes the whole way here.
Come on. Just…
- Thank you.
- Scusate. Where are you going?
Oh, see, this I could get used to.
For 1,000 euro a night, you can.
- Scusate.
- Oh!
- Signori.
- Right here. Quick, quick.
Sh. Sh. Sh. Sh.
Prego?
Oh, scusa! Sorry.
Down there. Quick.
The private event.
Some kind of photo shoot.
Hey, let's, um… let's blend in.
- Yes.
- Yeah?
Ooh, these look Italian.
What do you think? Yeah.
Get in there behind these guys. Yeah.
Oh, yes.
Marcello!
Goodness!
Hey, hey, hey. Hey. Here.
Oh. He's up there. Go, go, go, go, go.
Look, our overpricedcafféwith a view.
Ah!
- Delicious.
- Grazie.
- Excuse me.
- Thanks for the tour!
You'll look cool in these.
- I could get used toil dolce far niente.
- Mm.
Is that what's happening here?
Mm-hmm. I think so.
I mean, it's the perfect time
to brush up on our skills.
Fine. Bring it on, coach.
I was hoping you could coach me.
I'm the American here.
Okay.
Let me see if I can remember.
First, we relax.
Then we lean back.
- Mm.
- Oh, okay.
Yep. Mission accomplished. What's next?
We live in the moment.
No distractions.
Unwind.
I'm the worst unwinder ever.
Oh, I might be the second worst.
Hey, I'm impressed with us.
You know, no mishaps today.
We haven't fallen on top of one another
or gotten blasted with water, you know?
We still have all afternoon.
Plenty of time to get into trouble.
What kind of trouble did you have in mind?
I have some ideas.
It's my office.
Matteo?
Yes…
No, no, no. I'll come right now, yes.
Bye.
It's theAssessore Provincialestaff.
They want another walkthrough
of my new initiatives.
I have to go.
Okay.
Uh, listen, um… about today…
Yes, right. Uh, you mean the moment.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah. Um…
Well, we should definitely...
Not get involved.
As mayor, I'm in charge
of your one-euro house.
Well, technically,
it's… it's Olivia's one-euro house.
- It's still a conflict of interest.
- Got it.
And my life is complicated enough,
so we should keep it professional.
Yes, we will be
two very professional professionals.
- Professionals.
- Yeah.
Mm?
- Look at us, so mature.
- Well…
I really need to go now.
- Yes, of course.
- Yeah.
- I thought you were... I still don't have...
- It's… it's okay. It's fine.
- I... Okay.
- Just… ciao.
- Ciao.
- See you.
Hey!
Hey. I was wondering
where you were all day.
Yeah, just… Yeah.
Were you on a date?
What? No.
- Not a date, no.
- Mm-hmm.
But have you been dating?
Like, at all, back home?
Ooh! Uh, no. Yes!
No. I don't, uh…
I don't know what to say to you right now.
- Well, have you or haven't you?
- Uh…
Fine. Yes. Yes. Zola has set me up
a couple of times, but no sparks.
And the dating apps scare me.
- Yeah, welcome to the club.
- Yeah.
Wait. Are you absolutely positive
that wasn't a date?
- 'Cause I'm getting date vibe.
- Strictly business.
Yeah, plus, I think
she's with Bernardo anyway, so, um…
What did you do today?
- Uh, exterior paint for the shutters.
- Oh.
- That's it, nothing else.
- Okay.
I'm gonna get back to it.
Look at this.
This graph shows
how my sustainability projects
can eventually pay for themselves.
Francesca, you got this.
Grappa time?
Matteo!
Not every event calls for grappa.
- Ciao, Francesca.
- Bernardo.
- Grazie.
- Hey.
I stopped by earlier, but you were out.
Unusual for you.
I was on a professional visit.
What's going on
with the change-of-use permit
for the Field villa?
Eric says he hasn't seen you.
Ah, was he… your professional visit?
Olivia can't apply
for the commercial license
until the permit is squared away.
But Mario's house
wasn't even officially cleared
for the one-euro list.
And now this ridiculous idea
for a cooking school.
Why would anyone come here to cook?
Montezara can be
so much more than you imagine.
I wish you could see that.
Then convince me, ladybug.
Dinner?
I can't. I have to work all night.
Can we… have gelato this week?
Anytime. Bye.
- Bye.
- I never said that.
- Are you calling me crazy?
- Listen to me…
- Just say you think I'm crazy.
- No, no. But…
Nothing good on Netflix tonight?
Oh. Donata and I were supposed
to grab a glass of wine together, but…
I was about to enjoy some wine myself.
Want to join?
Sure.
Come on.
If you're trying to kidnap me,
you should know
I was my dojo's junior black belt champ.
- So…
- Not kidnapping you.
- But good to know about the black belt.
- Mm-hmm.
I'll make sure to watch my step.
Whoa.
Wow!
This is beautiful.
Sometimes I still can't believe it.
That I live here now in Italy.
- Montezara is a magical place.
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah, I'm gonna miss it if I go to Rome.
What's in Rome?
Can I trust you?
Of course.
- I'm very trustworthy.
- Mm-hmm?
It's part of my charm offensive.
I have an interview to become
an interior design apprentice.
Olivia! Fantastico!
Yeah, well, I'm not sure
my dad's gonna share your enthusiasm.
It's, like, his job
to disapprove of my life choices.
- Really? You seem close.
- Uh…
We used to be. When I was younger.
But…
I don't know. There are moments
in which I think we… we could be again.
I mean, I'm almost 25.
Why do I still care what he thinks anyway?
It's because you love him.
Yeah.
You're gonna dig this.
It's so cool.
From Greco's original blueprints.
Firewood storage for the oven.
- Go, Greco. That's a great idea.
- Right?
Yeah.
- Slowly. Come here, come on.
- Finally, it's here.
- Put it there.
- Come. Let's install it.
Oh, no, it is a sexy new fridge.
But I can't help today. I'm off to Rome.
Rome? That's not
on the schedule for today.
Uh, no. I'm meeting up
with an old college friend.
- Oh.
- In Rome.
Are you back tonight?
We could grab a bite...
I'm staying over. But I'll see you soon.
- Olivia…
- Bye!
- Yeah, be safe.
- Yeah.
Ah. Here we are.
Hey, Madam Mayor.
- Hi.
- Haven't seen you in ages.
- We miss your micromanaging.
- I doubt that.
- Well.
- Cooking with Gio today?
Yes. Uh, you? Late lunch?
- A nonworking one.
- Ah.
I'm still trying to practice
il dolce far niente.
- I just wrote up an agenda on my phone.
- Okay, that, uh, defeats the purpose.
But, as your coach,
I appreciate the effort. After you.
- Thank you.
- Mm.
- Buon appetito.
- Grazie.
- Bye, Francesca, thanks so much.
- Until next time.
- Ciao.
- Well?
I didn't look at my phone once.
I was so knocked out by this lunch.
Oh, I'm so glad you liked it.
We made it especially for you.
No.Signoreis being modest.
He made everything himself.
Good job.
Everything was exquisite.
Thank you so much.
I appreciate that.
Grazie.
You want to know a big secret?
You tried my first homemade mozzarella.
We have no secrets. Spill.
- I don't know how to cook.
- An Italian who doesn't know how to cook?
I store books in my oven. Tell no one.
They'll take away my citizenship.
And you mocked me for my microwave.
I was speaking from experience.
Ah!
Well, thanks for the help today.
I'm off. Standing date with mynonna.
Oh, that's sweet.
What do you guys do together?
Why don't you come?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
So you and your grandma drink together?
It's just anaperitivo.
A custom I brought from Rome.
- Nonnaand her friends demand it now.
- Wait. Nonnaand her friends?
- Your favorite grandson is here!
- Here he is!
- Ciao.
- I should have known.
- Granny's handsome boy!
- Uh…
- Grazie.
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh, grazie!
Only one drink,
then I must return to prep dinner service.
Okay.
Eric, do you have to rush off?
- I have the whole day.
- Oh, how beautiful.
And Antonia here was a professional baker.
And us two Antonias worked in her shop.
- Oh.
- I was the baker.
I was the first woman in Montezara
with her own business.
Wow. What happened to it?
We got old.
- We were put out to pasture.
- Wait.
I thought you liked
"the sweetness of doing nothing."
I'm bored out of my mind.
We want to be "Grandfluencers."
On the TikTok.
Hashtag: Goals. Right?
Right!
What is it?
Rodents. Angry chef.
I can take it.
I couldn't sleep,
so I came into the office.
- I was gonna wait till Monday to tell you…
- Tell me what?
I got a job offer from Deb Welch.
At Perfect Plate.
And, of course,
Northstar will wanna go with you.
Are you interested?
Maybe.
Look, I get why you went to Italy,
and I get why you stayed.
But I like being
on the same continent as my boss.
You gotta admit, you haven't had
your eye on the ball since you got there.
Yeah, got it.
I've definitely been reevaluating
some things while I've been here.
Zola, look, of course I want you to stay.
But you need to do what's right for you.
I told Deb I needed some time to think.
Good. Do that. I'm here.
- Let's connect before you get back to her.
- Okay.
Thanks.
You got it. Thank you.
Say, "I would like to go to Rome."
I would like to go to Rome.
- Vorrei an dare a Roma.
- I would like to go to Rome.
Ah!
- Hey!
- What's wrong withVecchia Strega?
- Oh, another flat tire.
I think she's not so subtly
trying to break up with me.
She's still pouting
over my bike excursion with you.
- She's such a drama queen.
- Yeah.
I'll have Matteo get her
patched up for you.
Oh, that'd be great.
What's this? Casual Saturday?
That's a new look. I like it.
- A beach party for my old friend, Pina.
- Oh.
She's always trying to get me
away from my desk.
I usually say no.
But someone helped coach you
on the sweetness of doing nothing.
Exactly.
I might need my coach's support.
You want to tag along?
Pina!
- Scusate. Francesca!
- Hey.
- Ciao!
You must be Eric.
- Yes.
- I've heard all about you.
- No, she hasn't.
- Yes, I have. Frozen pizza guy.
Here's to the birthday girl!
- Congratulations!
- Thank you.
Hey, there's
a philosophy life test I read about.
What do you feel
when you look at the ocean?
Your answer reveals
your, um, your outlook on life.
What do you feel?
What do I feel? Um…
Well, you plot your course in life,
but then a storm blows through
and the current takes you
somewhere totally different.
And you're left to… chart this new land.
And your turn.
Uh… I see something bigger
than I can understand.
Something I can't control.
No matter how big of a boat I can build
or… how much I consult my compass.
I can drown in the waves,
but they can lift me up
and take me to new places.
I got carried away.
No! What? That was incredible.
I knew there'd be dancing.
Oh man. You tricked me!
Shall we?
So, um,
about that two
"professional professionals" situation.
I never listen to politicians.
You're not coming up?
Um… you and Bernardo?
- Bernardo?
- Yeah.
He's just a friend.
Did he say otherwise?
- Well, not exactly, but...
- He's like a brother to me.
That's all.
Then, yes. I would love to come up.
- You're good at that.
- No, I've been watching Cesare.
There we go. Oh, Francesca.
There's something I need to know,
and it's, uh, it's very important.
- Books in your oven? Really?
- Oh!
I wasn't lying.
It's where I keep the ones
I don't want anyone to see on a bookshelf.
That is adorable. Oh my goodness.
Okay.
I have never eaten
anything this good before.
Of course not. American pastries
are an abomination.
I hear Dunkin' Donuts are good.
- Leave the fountain.
- Eh!
These are called "panforte."
- Panforte.
- Bravo.
Hmm. Oh!
While I was looking
for the villa blueprint,
look what I found.
No!
Hmm?
Look.
How pretty.
- We were so young.
- My goodness.
It's time to unretire.
- Teach at our cooking school.
- No!
Become… "Grandfluencers."
Wow!
This was
Olivia's favorite as a kid.
Really? This beige dish is good?
Italian food should not be beige.
Uh-huh. I know
it's not how the Italians cook it.
Just try it.
This fettuccine Alfredo is, uh,
not too bad.
But I will deny ever saying as much.
Uh-huh. Oh!
Let me guess. Francesca?
- How did you know?
- You've been smiling all day.
That smile means only one thing.
L'amore.
- L'amore.
- Mm-hmm.
I still haven't figured out
how to tell Olivia.
- Tell me what?
- Uh…
- Ooh, Dad's Thursday night surprise.
- Uh-huh.
- Eric's teaching me to cook American.
- Oh, is he?
- You headed off to Rome again?
- Oh right. Did you get the apprenticeship?
What apprenticeship?
Olivia. I thought he knew by now.
Thought I knew what?
What's he talking about?
Um…
Come on.
Let's talk.
Hey.
What's going on?
I've been going to Rome
to meet with a colleague of Nino's.
His name is Carlo.
He's an interior designer
and wants to take on an apprentice.
- Me.
- Hmm.
I know it looks like I'm bailing again.
- But...
- I think that is amazing, Liv.
Oh. Okay.
Uh… I wasn't expecting that.
I gotta hand it to you.
I mean, you learned on the job.
Just like you said you would.
I wish you felt you could've told me.
When did we stop?
You know, confiding in each other?
I don't know.
I guess… Mom was always the glue.
- Yeah.
- Our go-between.
And then… she was gone.
So we got… glueless.
It's my fault. I couldn't figure out
how to talk to you without her.
No.
It's not all on you.
We both grieved differently.
I didn't understand
that you mourned Mom by…
Well, I would have called it screwing off,
but I don't know,
maybe you were just figuring it out?
Yeah. And…
…you mourned her by shutting down.
- Liv, I'm so sorry for the time we missed.
- Look, you're here now.
And you stuck it out.
Even when I didn't want you to.
Yeah. Well, in the spirit of…
coming clean...
- You're dating Francesca?
- What? How did you know?
Please!
You thought I didn't notice
when I came back from Rome
and you hadn't slept here?
Okay, honestly, it's new.
- Uh, I promise...
- Dad, chill.
I'm not upset.
And besides, I…
I love Francesca. She's awesome.
My bat radar must be broken.
I… I was so worried
that you were gonna feel like I was…
I don't know, trying to replace Mom. Uh…
Dad, you're still young… ish.
Of course you were gonna meet someone new.
That doesn't make
what you and Mom had any less special.
What I had with your mom
was once in a lifetime.
But you still have a lot of lifetime left.
I know.
- Look at you.
- Hmm?
You're cooking again.
- You're dating again.
- Mm-hmm.
You're happy.
And it pains me to admit this,
but… I do like having you around.
That's really nice to hear.
Maybe the curse is lifted.
- Wait.
- Hmm?
What if you stayed in Italy? Hear me out.
The apprenticeship is just for one year.
I'm gonna need someone to help
manage the villa cooking lessons
and help Gio in the kitchen.
I can't do that, can I?
Oh, I've just had my head
in the business for so long that...
and now this cooking school, I mean…
Could I really make such a huge change?
At my age?
I don't know.
Why not?
You know, Dad,
when Mom and I dreamt about the villa…
Mm-hmm?
…It wasn't just for her and me.
It was for the three of us.
Ah, she's always around us somehow.
Like here in the garden, just… listening.
- I like that.
- Me too.
But if you talk to her first,
don't tell her about my tattoo.
No, my lips are sealed.
All right,
see you Wednesday at 2:00. Bye.
You're dating Eric Field.
Yes, it's new.
But…
…I haven't had the chance to tell anyone.
- What about you and me?
- You know how I feel.
I thought it was because
you were still mourning Alessandro.
I didn't think I wanted a relationship.
But we have history. And he's leaving…
The truth is that
Eric's actually thinking about staying.
To run the cooking school.
The cooking school? But...
You had doubts, I know.
I may have asked too much of you.
Anyway, in the end, I did it myself…
And got the change-of-use permit.
Listen…
On Saturday,
they are doing the fresco reveal.
You helped this first
one-euro house be a success.
I would like you to come.
Anyway, bye.
Hey. Where's Donata?
It's, uh, it's weird
not navigating a sea of broken pottery.
Finished. For good.
Oh man. I'm sorry.
I was rooting for you guys.
You know, a wise woman once told me
anything worth loving
is worth fighting for.
And you kids,
you… you fight all the time, so…
You're a genius.
You're a genius, Eric.
Thank you very much!
Be careful.
Coming.
Okay. Um…
- Put that here, please.
- Yes.
- All right.
- Oh, uh… Those four over there.
- Here.
- Thank you!
Sure.
Oh!
- Nice.
- Yeah.
Don't make me regret this name, girl.
Eh-oh… ladies and gentlemen,
the final piece.
Wow, guys!
- Bellissimo!
- That looks amazing.
What do you think?
Magnifico.
Oh, it's beautiful, huh?
So beautiful. Mwah!
Oh. Hey, this calls for a celebration.
- Yes!
- Hey!
- Bernardo, you made it.
- Sorry I'm late.
I had to pick up our two guests
from the train station.
Larry and Tracey Longo.
Oh no.
They can't be.
Oh, they are.
Grumpy Mario's American heirs.
And the rightful owners of this villa.
Hi.
Okay, here.
Documentation that
my great-great-great grandma,
Maria Leoni, is from Montezara,
born July 6th, 1867.
And the town of Montezara contacted us
about being potential heirs.
Yes, it was us. Multiple times.
You never responded.
Oh, well, we didn't realize
it was urgent.
But then Bernardo sent us
pictures of the rehabbed villa.
- What have you done?
- I warned you, Francesca.
You shouldn't have "sold" this property
before the claim window closed.
Let me understand.
You never returned
countless calls or emails
when the house was in disrepair.
And now that it's totally renovated,
you're interested.
Okay, sure. Uh, whatever.
It doesn't make the villa any less ours.
We've already hired a lawyer.
Oh my God, does this place have a pool?
Dad.
Let's all
just take a breath here, okay?
Yes, Mr. and Mrs. Longo.
I will put you up in a hotel
on Montezara's dime
while I verify all your paperwork.
Let's go. Come on.
- I promise I will figure this out.
- Yep.
Mario's great-grandmother
was Maria Leoni, born in 1867.
That would make Larry Longo
the closest living relative.
So the relatives in Italy
weren't actually allowed
to donate the land.
This isn't looking good. Not good at all.
Not now. Not now, Matteo. Please.
Cases
of disputed abandoned property
have become a big issue
with the one-euro program.
But we're the ones who renovated.
And invested the money. Olivia's money.
- They can just take it?
- Unfortunately, they probably can.
Italian inheritance laws
are on their side.
Well, what can we do?
Well, you can sue
for reimbursement for your costs.
Is there no chance of holding on?
It sounds like the Longos
have compelling evidence of ancestry.
Almost all these cases tend to drag on,
with substantial costs
and a great deal of court time.
Got it. All right, well, I appreciate it.
Thank you for the consultation.
Wish I had better news.
- Yeah.
- Ciao.
Well, look, we can fight.
Liv, I can cash in my 401K.
No. No, no.
It's okay, and I appreciate it,
but… I think it's the end of the road.
Or, as they say, all roads lead to Rome.
You have an apprenticeship
because of this place.
Yeah, but…
What will you do?
Well, I'll go to Rome as well.
But to catch a plane.
Back to Columbus. Back to my business.
Hopefully, convince Zola to stay.
- Make her partner.
- What about this?
Your cooking.
Ah, Liv, you know,
with you and me both here…
I thought we could create a new home.
That I could have a new life.
But clearly, that's not meant to be.
And Francesca?
Oh, I don't know.
Ah, we haven't been together that long.
It's a lot. It's a lot
to hang on someone so fast, you know?
But I want you to be happy.
Oh! Oh-oh.
It's a dad's job
to make sure you're happy.
And I know…
I know you're all grown up
but you'll always be BatDad's little girl.
Okay?
Hey.
We were surprised you reached out.
Yeah, look, um…
I'll cut to the chase.
Olivia and I have no desire
to spend years in court
fighting over this villa that we love,
so we have an offer for you.
Olivia invested her inheritance
from her late mother to rehab this place.
Oh. We're so sorry for your loss.
If you reimburse her,
we will turn over the villa
and vacate immediately.
- It's a bit more than one euro now.
- Come on, are you serious?
But it is still a steal at this price.
So, do we have a deal?
Eric!
There you are.
I went to speak to the Longos,
but I heard they already spoke to you.
What happened?
Uh…
We made a deal.
They're going to reimburse Olivia
for the renovation,
and then, uh, we'll… turn over the deed.
I'm mortified.
- This is all my fault. You must hate me.
- No. Look, you…
You took a leap of faith. You're just
trying to save this town. I get it.
- But the villa, it was Olivia's dream.
- She's gonna be okay.
She's smart and resilient,
and… and she's still going to Rome
for that apprenticeship, so…
Yeah, good. She's going to Rome?
- Yeah.
- That's good.
And you?
Uh…
Yeah, I think, um…
I think I need to go
back to Ohio, probably.
Yeah, I see. I…
- That's what I thought. You'd eventually...
- I mean, I wish...
No, no, no. I get it.
We let the current carry us off course.
I have one job to do, and it's be mayor.
Maybe we should have kept it
professional professionals.
No.
No!
How could I?
How could I make such a mess of this?
Antonia.
Pass her your "medicine."
What "medicine?"
You're not fooling anyone!
I blame Grumpy Mario.
The Leoni family was always so rude.
No, Antonia, that was the Leone family.
You're confused, Antonia.
The Leone family was simply lovely.
What did you say?
- There was a Leoni family, with an "I"?
- Yes.
- And a Leone family with an "e"?
The mayor just stole my "medicine!"
Matteo… did you know there used to be
a Leone family in town? With an "e"?
Wait, are you thinking…?
Maybe Larry Longo's
great-great-grandmother's surname
was changed when she emigrated to America.
I hear that was a common mistake.
There's only one way to find out.
Madam Mayor?
Matteo, not now.
I'm searching for the census binders.
The 1860s are all missing…
I brought coffee.
And reinforcements.
Here we are.
Anything to help the Fields.
And anything to help you.
Thank you, guys.
Let's get to work.
- Come on.
- Okay. Yes.
Hey.
I'm all packed, ready to head out.
- I'm gonna miss you.
- Same.
- Hmm.
- I'm so glad we had this time.
Me too.
Uh, what are we gonna do about Maltese?
Oh, uh, Donata's going to take her.
- Oh.
- They have matching tempers, so…
They do.
Ooh. Um…
Is it cool if I don't walk you
to the train station?
I kinda wanna pretend
like you're still here.
It's cool.
Oh…
Hey, guys. I found these
under the sink in the bathroom.
Ew, gross! No. Mildew. No.
Oh, stop it.
These are the ones!
Genius!
Each of you take one, quickly!
Good job, my love!
1867…
1867! Guys! Come over here!
Maria "Leon-i,"
was born on March 17th, 1867.
Grumpy Mario's grandmother.
Maria "Leon-e" was born
on July 6th of the same year.
Her family left for America
when she was seven years old.
That's Larry Longo's relative!
Yes!
Grappa!
- What time is it?
- Eh, 10:05.
Eric's leaving on the 10:10.
There's no reception.
I'll never make it in time.
Yes, you will. You have a secret weapon.
Let's go!
- Vecchia Strega!
- Thanks.
Go get your man!
Go! Go!
Buongiorno.
You got off the train.
No, I never got on.
Here's the thing.
I didn't think I could ever have…
feelings like this again. And then…
And then I met you.
Olivia and I lost the villa,
but I don't wanna lose you too.
I love you.
I love you too.
And you haven't lost the villa.
What?
I have something to show you.
So all of this
because of one letter?
Oh, the good news
is that the Leone family, not Leoni,
also left property in Montezara.
- Hmm.
- That's so exciting.
As the rightful heir, Larry… it's yours.
Villa Leone slash Longo.
It's a dump.
But it's our dump, baby.
I can feel
my family's legacy all around us.
- Exactly. Montezara's a feeling.
- Yes!
You… you said you like your contractor?
Oh yeah.
He's the best and only contractor in town.
And as for permits, we have
a newgeometrastarting next week.
Oh, what happened to Bernardo?
Uh… he decided to move to Milan.
- We miss him.
- Yeah.
So, hon. What do you think, huh?
As long as I get a pool.
So what do you think?
- I like it.
- Well, I'm definitely in.
Well then, congratulations,
co-chairs of the newly merged
Main Course and Perfect Plate Consulting.
Wow, that's a mouthful.
We'll work on a new name.
Meanwhile, we need you
to hit the ground running,
starting up the Italian division
of our business.
You got it, bosses.
Ooh, I like the sound of that!
Montezara
has the new cooking school.
And we're expanding
the one-euro house program.
Testa Travel,
an all-electrical vehicle company,
is adding our town as a stop on its route.
I project a budget surplus by next year.
Thank you.
It seems you'll need
those EV charging stations after all.
Grappa time!
Finally!
All right!
Here we go, the Olivia Special!
Pizzas!
Thank you.
Look how beautiful she is.
Let's go!
Oh, hey! You guys made it.
Antonia!
Like my dad used to say…
Mic drop! Boom!
Eric, I actually learned how to cook.
- You did?
- You know what this means?
- It means I need to learn how to dance.
- Yes!
Let's go.